Carson Bruce

View at carson.kiwi

I am passionate about creating simple and beautiful apps.

I plan and deliver throughout the entire software development process, from when a project is imagined to its release. I've worked on a number of large projects, demonstrating my experience through a range of roles.

My key attributes include: problem solving, speed and passion to learn, open mindedness, and being a team player.

I am an early adopter of JavaScript, React, Angular, Node.js, and Express, embracing the continuing shift towards simpler and more agile systems and processes.

I am at home when working with and sharing JavaScript along with all the technologies and processes it enables.

Get in touch at hello@carson.kiwi

Experience

Solnet

Aug 2012 - Now (5 years)

I started at Solnet a week out from graduating, kicking off the role in the delivery team of the company. I have gained experience with several high profile clients, placed first as a front end developer along with other roles such as Devops Developer, API Developer, Automation Tester, and UX Designer. More recently in my time at Solnet I have been mentoring team members in JavaScript tooling and practices, through 1-on-1 catch ups and wider group presentations.

Take a look at the Projects section to see some of the work I've done with Solnet.

Research Project: Query Expansion

Nov 2011 - March 2012 (4 months)

My second research opportunity was offered by the supervisor of my honours project. The project looked at ways that Wikipedia and its hyperlinks could be used to support query expansion; by better interpreting a users query and reformulating it to improve the results retrieved. With some give-and-take from the Web Intelligence team at Victoria, I managed to get the paper submitted and accepted to an Australasian Web Intelligence conference.

Research Project: Eye Gaze tracking

Nov 2010 - March 2011 (4 months)

At the end of my 300 level university year I was awarded a research scholarship. With the support of my supervisor and his team, I contributed to the development of an open source gaze tracking system. This helped it evolve to a level where it could benefit the university, saving an equivalent commercial product cost of approximately \$10,000.

Cool Bananas

Nov 2009 - March 2010 (4 months)

During an internship with a fellow student and senior software engineer, we prototyped a scripting interpreter and runtime for embedded systems. The experience helped cement the years study learning C, Agile Processes, and Testing Practices. The project proved successful when it gained further funding to be developed into a commercial product.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Software Engineering, First Class Honours

Victoria University of Wellington

2007-2012

Projects

Lending and Onboarding

BNZ

I joined a team at BNZ to help in transforming their Lending and Onboarding systems, aiming to improve the experience for customers and bank staff. This transformation was supported by a new way of delivery, promoting more modular systems design and implementation with supporting Platforms and Devops processes. I shared the lead for the Front-end implementation of two major applications and a component library.

- Pioneered application development seeing Angular 2 through its beta releases.
- Promoted and adapted a UI component library for multiple applications.
- · Guided Front-end developers through best practices, process and tooling.
- Guided UI Integration testers through best practices, process and tooling.
- Followed and fed back into areas close to UI to ensure smoother transitions including UX, Platforms, Devops, and API.
- · Involved in successfully delivering the systems first release.

Employment Agreement Builder

Ministry of Business and Innovation and Employment

EAB is an application for small to medium businesses to create new Employment agreements while learning about employment law with easy-to-digest content. I worked on this as a JavaScript developer in a small team, guiding another developer and automation tester with the language and tooling. The project exceeded its objectives and was built, tested, and delivered in three months.

- Practiced BDD and TDD ending up with a feature complete integration and unit test suite.
- · Created and published a decoupled CMS component.
- · Created a reusable data-driven forms solution reused for a second MBIE Policy Builder application.
- · Sold a full stack JavaScript solution to architects.
- Implemented a Node.js micro service handling 10x expected load.
- Implemented a CI environment that performed automated testing and releasing a dozen times a day.
- Pushed a docker solution bringing build and deployment time down to minutes rather than hours.

Online Banking

Westpac

I was part of a Westpac team to evolve their online banking experience, originally rolled in as an IBM Worklight consultant and dev ops engineer. I helped keep the project oiled by mediating communications between developers from API and Front-end teams. I improved automation in local, development, and test environments helping developers become more autonomous. After two months my role extended to a technical lead of a team of five, responsible for feature development in the middleware.

- Presented and owned the solutions of several developer tooling and experience improvements.
- Technical leader and mentor of a team of five covering a wide spread of technologies and environments.
- Trusted as the gatekeeper of critical development and test environments relied on by a team of 60.
- Implemented a JavaScript middleware framework that improved the reuse and reliability of the middleware HTTP adapters.
- Implemented the security feature encompassing the client and middleware layers.
- Presented a UX review noting several usability and performance improvements for the application.

NEON is Sky TV's entry into the New Zealand TV on demand market. Our project's team was responsible for implementing the Front-end and the API supporting other NEON apps sitting on different platforms. My role was a Front-end developer with a close interest in the Web API and UX layers.

- . Worked with the Front-end team to implement an angular application within Liferay
- Designed API transforming PAAS data sources to support the multiple clients
- · Presented UX and design alternatives to client.
- · Worked remotely for half the project.
- Managed my time effectively within a time pressured environment.

Crew Forms

Air New Zealand

The Crew Forms application looked to turn a paper based form into a mobile tablet-based solution. The experience of these forms was improved with the new technology and with a change in platform the forms were able to be re-imagined to provide a better user experience. I worked on the project in its second phase, bringing in new features and tidying the first implementation.

- Polished up the app correcting dozens of rendering bottlenecks, resulting in a jank-free hybrid solution.
- . Worked with the UX and Design team to best fit solutions with the technology stack.
- · Extended the apps feature list and matching test coverage.
- · Provided solutions to bugs found within open source libraries

Name learning game

Private

We entered in a competition to imagine, design, and develop a proof of concept mobile gamification app in 3 days. The brief was to create an educational tool that would help staff learn the names of their clients. We placed well in the competition, gaining access to the company's evaluation panel for future projects. Shortly after Solnet made a winning proposal for a separate project.

- Created a proof of concept application in 3 days.
- Succeeded in gaining a position on the client's project panel.
- Worked effectively with other JavaScript, UX and UI developers in parallel streams.

Interests

JavaScript	User Experience	Netball	Running
Cycling	Photography	Gaming	Sound systems
	Beer brewing	Stenciling	

hello@carson.kiwi

GitHub https://github.com/Kauabunga Linkedin https://nz.linkedin.com/in/carsonbruce